A Guide to the Records of Virginia First Lady Pamela Northam, 2018-2021.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia First Lady Pamela Northam,
2018-2021.
The Library of Virginia
53522
Virginia. Office of the Governor.
.7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions. Must have permission of photographer to obtain copies of photographs.
Acquisition Information
Accession 53529 was transferred by the Office of the Governor, 12 Jan 2022.
Historical Information
Pamela Northam became First Lady when her husband Ralph Northam was sworn in as Virginia Governor on January 13, 2018 and served until January 2021. She attended Baylor University and Universtiy of Texas and prior to becoming First Lady worked as pedriatic occupational therapist, science educator, and a community outreach coordinator. As First Lady, Pamela Northam chaired the Children's Cabinet and led the Northam Administration's work on improving early childhood education in Virginia.
Staff for the First Lady included David Cary, Chief of Staff; Danielle Campbell, Confidential Assistant; Natalie Chapman, Executive Assistant; and Bailey Harlow, Executive Assistant.
Scope and Content
Records of Virginia First Lady Pamela Northam, 2018-2021, are housed in two boxes and are arranged alphabetically. These records document the work of the First Lady and include, but are not limited to agendas, budget requests, correspondence, executive orders, governor decision requests, legislation, meeting briefs, memoranda, notes, presentations, promotional materials, schedules, speeches and talking points.
Some topics include child care centers, conservation, Covid 19, early childhood education, federal preschool grants, gun violence prevention, Headstart, healthy lifestyles for the state workforce, school safety. Includes records related to various initiatives of the Northam Administration including Children's Cabinet, Early Childhood Advisory Committee (ECAC), Early Childhood Education, Virginia Kindergarten Readiness Program (VKRP), and the Virginia Preschool Initiative (VPI).
Contents List
- Records of Virginia First Lady Pamela Northam, 2018-2021.
  - Budget requests, 2018-2021. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Children's Cabinet, 2018-2019. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Children's Cabinet - Meeting, 2019 Dec 2. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Circle Pre-School Program, undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comprehensive Early Childhood Reporting, 2020. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Conservation Cabinet - Meeting, 2019 May 13. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Covid 19, 2020. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early Childhood Education Planning, 2017-2019. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Early Childhood Education Workforce - Philadelphia, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Executive Orders, 2018-2019. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - First House: Two Centuries with Virginia's First Families (DVD), 2013. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Assembly, 2019. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Assembly, 2020. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Assembly, 2021. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Assembly, 2022. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Governance Models (School Readiness Committee), undated. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019-2020. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Governor's Early Childhood Education Package, 2020. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Imagination Station (Pearisburg), undated. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 2018-2021. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes and drawings from children, undated. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - Onancock School Arts Center (DVD), 2018 Feb 3. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Gunston Hall (flash drive), 2018 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Eastville CHC, 2018 Aug 15. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reston Children's Center, undated. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scheduling, 2018; 2020. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - School Readiness Committee, 2018 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 2019; undated. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - State Employee Child Care, 2019. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - STEM Commission, 2019. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Thank you notes, 2018-2019. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Trade Mission to the United Kingdom, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Transition briefing, 2017 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 14)